I think you've made some acknowledgments
that there's some form of rebuilding
mode or, you know, restocking mode or
whatever the right term is for that in
the last year or two.
>> Does that change your philosophy on on
on the aggressiveness of trading up that
that you've obvious?
>> No, not really.
>> Or the belief that more picks is is
needed or better or anything like that?
>> No, I don't I don't think it it does. um
we're going to approach this the same
way. And look, I say this every year,
we're not opposed to backing up if it
makes sense to us, but um it hadn't made
sense to us the last few years.
>> There's been a talk of, you know, arm
length for uh you know, defensive
lineman, especially a guy like Ruben
Bane. When you you know, analyze
defensive linemen, how much does that
kind of play a role into things? And is
there, you know, certain circumstances
where a player's tape could, you know,
overmatch any, you know, quote unquote
sure arms?
>> Yeah, I I think I think what, you know,
how the guy plays
always overrides everything. So, let's
let's, you know, start with that. Um,
but I do think this, we've got a lot of
data um that tells us what plays in the
NFL, and this isn't exclusive to um the
defensive line. It's all the positions.
We know what plays in the NFL and we
have some some measurements that that
that
we can look at and say, "Man, that's an
outlier."
We're not looking for outliers. You
know, I I say this to our guys, I've
said this over the years, if we are
looking for exceptions, then we're not
going to be here very long because
exceptions are exceptions. So, we're not
looking for exceptions. But we recognize
that there are exceptions. And so if
someone has uh some traits that don't
match what plays in the NFL, then we
better have some other things that tell
us that he can overcome that. And so um
yeah, that's my answer to that.
>> You staying at number eight in this
year's drafts. How much do you like his
position in the draft? How is it for
this particular class? Well, I don't
like it because it mean it means that
last year didn't go very well. So, um
you don't want to be picking in the top
10, but once you know, you get to the
draft and you look at the quality of the
players that exist. Um yeah, you get
excited about I know we're going to get
a really good player at at pick eight.
Um so, you get excited about that. A guy
that can have an impact on your team.
>> Yeah. How do you guys like define the
unknowns that you can't maybe see on
film? like a guy that you think might be
able to rush a passer but he's only
maybe has like 20 snaps of it or someone
you think might be able to drop back but
hasn't done a whole lot of it.
>> Um well I think that gets back to traits
versus you know what you've actually
seen and and look this is where
sometimes the off season comes into play
in terms of the workouts the the the
measurables you know the things that
tell you yeah a guy can do something
that maybe he hasn't been asked to do
yet. Um,
and there's it's a balance, right? It's
a balance.
>> Where uh, do you look at I guess your
thought process is you talked about the
exceptions. Picking in the top 10, you
don't do that that often. Are you more
prone to be we follow certain guidelines
in the top 10, maybe we could be a
little bit more exceptions at 28 than we
could at 8?
>> Yeah, I think you're I think for us,
we're probably a little more risk
averse. Um,
you know, when we when we make a pick
there, we want to have a lot of the
questions answered
uh about a player.
You don't want to pick a player that you
have a ton of questions about and you're
just, you know, banking on on uh, you
know, the unknown. Um,
so I I think as you go farther back in
the draft, you're a little more willing
to take a chance on someone. Um, but I
think in, you know, when you're in the
top 10 or top 12, whatever the number
is, you want to, uh, pick players that
you have, um, as little doubt as
possible that they're going to be
successful.
>> Does the timer going from 10 minutes to
8 minutes in the first round change like
the leg work you have to do on trades
and stuff ahead of the draft?
>> No, I I don't really I mean, I don't
know yet. I mean, we went from 15 to 10
at one point, and I didn't feel like
that had a big impact. Um,
I I don't think it will, but we'll see.
Um,
>> yeah, we'll see what happens.
>> A couple positions
>> that make this trap a little deeper. Um,
you know, I I don't know that I can say
that because deeper than what I meant,
you know, last year or the year before
or, you know, obviously there's fewer
quarterbacks being talked about in the
first round, so that changes the dynamic
a little bit, but
you know, and and I I hear sometimes,
you know, ah, this isn't a very deep
draft. I seem like I hear that every
year from different people and I kind of
feel like that's a little bit of an
excuse that if the draft doesn't go
well. Um I think there's good players in
every draft. I think there's guys that
are going to be Pro Bowl type players
and it's our job to identify them and
then hopefully we have an opportunity to
take them.
>> Hey Mickey, you had uh your staff a lot
of your staff senior bowl time as coach.
>> Yeah.
>> Um did you feel like you had a head
start on everybody else? Yeah, I think I
think it's uh uh look, we did have a lot
of coaches uh at the Senior Bowl and at
the East West game and and uh look,
that's development opportunity for those
coaches,
but it's a a great opportunity for us to
um you know, get get more information on
players that are going to be prominent
in this draft. And uh so that was really
good for us.
>> Speaking of things you probably hear
every year, uh a lot of people think
next year's draft class is really
stacked. Do you try to have a beat on
that when you're value?
>> No, I think it just changes and stuff
like that.
>> Um, not really. Uh, I mean, I'll ask
that question now and then of Jeff and
say, "Hey, what does next year look like
in terms of a position or or overall,
but I don't know that it's a it's a u
it's not that prominent in terms of when
we're we're making those discussions
just because things change so much over
the course of uh uh the college season."
on the opposite side of that. Um the
class you had last year, immediate
impact guys, not as impactful as like
2017 or 06, but the fact that you had a
class with so much immediate impact and
got your quarterback. How does that
alter and make you want to have a proper
class to follow them up this year?
>> Yeah, I mean I I don't think it changes
anything. We always want to have a great
draft class. Um,
you know, I thought it was great for our
scouts and and Jeff and and his uh
people to get recognized for for last
year's success. Um,
but it doesn't have any impact on what
we're doing this year.
>> Yesterday, um, Tyler Shuck talked about
like how he's been evaluating receivers
like how much input do you all let him
have like how involved his head? Yeah, I
mean, look, we we'll ask any of our
players that have a crossover with
someone in this draft, you know, and
it's always the young guys that played
with someone. If they've played with
someone, we talk to them about about,
hey, what kind of guy is he, you know,
what how did how did he, you know,
learn? How did he uh practice? You know,
so we asked questions of all our guys.
It wasn't just Tyler. Um,
>> you know, it's everybody on our team
that has a crossover with a player
that's in this draft that we may have um
an interest in in. How many scenarios do
you guys prepare for? Like what's your
like you know
>> how many mock drafts do we do
>> like a hundred
>> when there when there's new like trade
rumors? Does do you go back and then
start looking through different
scenarios and how things might
>> Yeah, a little bit. Um and look, here's
one great thing about the technology
now. We can just push a button and do
mock drafts. We don't have to, you know,
bring all of our scouts in a room and
assign them teams and then they make the
pick. you know, we have this technology
that allows us to uh to do these mock
drafts and and we do a lot of them. We
do um and so there's a lot of different
scenarios, particularly in the uh the
mid to later rounds, you know, because
that's that's where it gets a little I
don't want to say dicey, but that's
probably the only word I can think of um
as to what may happen.
uh Sean Peyton's involvement in the
draft was pretty obvious and then and
then it seemed like Dennis Allen as well
and he had been here for so long and the
collaborative what what was your
philosophy and what is your philosophy
when you bring in Kell Moore is new to
the organization never been a head coach
are you right away like you know I want
you to have as strong a voice in this as
anyone is it more this year than last
year like how how
>> it was no different than when Sean first
got us got with us right he was a new
coach and I want the coaches involved I
want them. Um, I want to get their
perspective and if we have differences,
um, you know, between the personnel
department and the coaching staff, we
got to we got to get those ironed out
before we we pick a player. You know,
our goal is to all be on the same page
in terms of the players that we bring in
here because that gives them and us the
best chance for them to be successful in
my opinion. when it comes to weighing
things with what you all were able to
accomplish in in free agency. Is that
has that shifted anything with just like
your like how you're evaluating some
prospects? What what maybe you be or
more out of that especially with the
right pick? I assume you wanted to be a
starter on the team.
>> Yeah, I I think it it look it certainly
affects us in terms of as we get later
in the draft, you know, you're trying
to, you know, fill slots on your roster.
I don't think it impacts us so much at
the top of the draft because, you know,
we're looking to take the best player
that's available to us when we pick. Um,
but as I've said before, generally
speaking, there's, you know, when you
when it's time to pick, you've got two
or three guys that you're choosing from
that are all in that same grade area and
then you look at your roster and say,
"Hey, we need somebody at this position
more than the other one." So, um, it
definitely impacts it. Um,
but it's not like the only impact.
>> When it comes out of things that are
kind of premium and non-premium
positions, as people like to talk about,
often times, uh, slot corner is usually
defined as nonpremium. Is that different
for you all because of how Brandon Sy
uses that position in his defense?
>> Um,
may maybe a little bit. I I wouldn't say
it's significantly different, but um
yeah, may but I'd say maybe a little
different. Yes. I mean, you have to pay
attention to the schemes you're running
and and and what you know, your coaching
staff values
um in terms of what they're trying to
get accomplished. So, yeah, it does have
some impact.
>> I noticed in Baton Rouge, uh you chat
with Monsour Delane, you were there for
his impressive proday. um what did you
think of him and and what kind of
addition do you think he would uh add to
an NFL team?
>> Yeah. Um look, I don't want to get into
a discussion about specific players, but
look, I I had a good talk with him. He's
impressive young man. Um I talked to him
about some of the things that he was
doing, you know, in the offseason and
and look, he he was great. He had great
answers and obviously a really good
player that's going to get taken high.
Going back to the draft philosophy now
due to what you did in free agency, the
fact that you address so many needs, how
much does that freed you up to get best
player available instead of just best
player we need?
>> Yeah, I I think I've said this in prior
years, our goal in the offseason is
always to be in the position where we
can take, particularly at the top of the
draft, um the best player available. And
if we have to build a strength on our
team, then that's okay. Um, and so I
think this year probably as much as any
year, you know, we were able to do a few
things that allows us to do that.
>> You, uh, or I guess historically in the
league, you see trades up for
quarterbacks knowing that I assume
there's a quarterback going one and then
after that talks may not be about
quarterbacks. Has that been different
for you all or other teams or just
historically what you've seen because
people aren't moving up for the
quarterback?
Um, I don't know yet because I think
most of those calls start coming, you
know, today and tomorrow. Um, before the
draft, more so than than prior to
obviously, you know, we've heard from
some teams about teams that, hey, we
might want to move back here. Uh, a few
teams that that might want to move up,
not just in the first round, but but in
the second as well. Um,
you know, it remains to be seen,
you know, how much of that activity
occurs, but I wouldn't say it's a lot
different um than the past. But again,
you know, picking in the top 10 is a
different it's a different uh, you know,
thing than picking in the middle or or
back half of the round. So, you you get
fewer calls when you're back there as
opposed to when you're in the in the top
10. How do you evaluate a prospect that
might be healing with an injury during
the pre-draft process?
>> Yeah, that I think that's difficult
sometimes because you you don't have as
much information, so it creates more
questions, right? Um
but I think, you know, at the combine um
you know, the medical people do a really
good job of assessing uh injuries, so we
have a pretty good handle uh on on guys
that are hurt and what their timelines
are. Um but there may be some unanswered
questions in terms of some of these
measurables that that we value.
>> U there is a report that um Nusmeer is
going to spend the draft with his son
until he gets drafted.
>> Yeah. It is that a situation where he
still kind of works from afar and you'll
call to get his opinion or being the
situation's so rare, do you just kind of
let him unplug and
>> Yeah. No, listen, Doug Doug's going to
be available to us. Um and his input's
valuable. We've gotten most of that.
Look, all these questions that may come
up in the draft are mostly answered. And
so, um, you know, I don't anticipate
I don't anticipate a lot of questions
coming at, you know, when we're on the
clock or during the draft, but I know
Doug will be available and we value his
input.
>> Attention to division, what they're
doing.
>> Not much really. I mean, we note it
obviously, but we don't have any control
over that. So, um, you know, it is what
it is really.
>> How did the, uh, decision to let Doug
spend it with Derek kind of come about?
Was it Ken's idea, your idea? Like, how
did it,
>> um, you know, I I don't know. That's a
good question. Um, so, but look, I get
that, you know,
you I advise him to spend it with
Garrett. It's a once in a-lifetime
opportunity. How do you think um the
draft may impact with what you guys want
to do with Alvin or or guy like Cam
unsettled guys?
>> Yeah, I I think that it could impact it.
Um you know, we'll see what happens. Uh
and that goes both ways. It that may
impact them uh from their perspective as
well as ours.
>> That it
Yeah, I don't we don't want to get into
any of that right now. You know, that's
we'll we'll do that after the draft. We
got a lot of questions that we got to
get answered over the next few few days
relative to our roster and and then
we'll go from there.
>> I I was going to ask about Cam Jordan
and Taesm Hill. Has there been any
resolution or they fall in the after the
draft?
>> Yeah, I you know, look, those those are
two-way questions, right? They have
things that they have to uh determine
and we do too. So, um we'll see what
happens after the draft. Mickey, you
were saying the first round, you got two
or three guys with the same kind of
grade as the draft goes on, third,
fourth, fifth round. Is that bullpen of
players grow a little bit?
>> Um, yeah. I think it I think Well, you
hope it does. I mean, when we get to
the, you know, fifth and sixth round,
I'm hoping that we have four or five
guys that we can choose from. But
sometimes, you know, you get down there
and there's one guy that you that stands
out above all the rest. Um,
but you're hoping that you have four or
five because then you know the holes
that you have on your roster come into
play.
>> How much do you think last year's
success of the draft I mean it was like
one of the rare years you didn't trade
at all? I mean was it just having more
picks to marrier like or was there
something about the process that
>> um I I mean I don't know. I mean, we
made some trades in ' 06, and that was a
pretty good draft. And I don't remember
if we made trades in 17 or not, but that
was a good draft, too. So, um,
yeah, I've said this before, man. If we
love somebody and and we feel like it's
necessary to make a move, then we're
going to do that.
>> What do you think of, uh, the receiver
depth in this draft this year?
>> Yeah, I'm Look, I think it's good. It's
it's it's, you know, what I said before,
there's going to be good players in this
draft no matter what you think about
that depth. Um, and it's up to us to get
get them identified and then hopefully,
you know, we have the opportunity to
take those guys. Um, but I I I do think
there's a lot of good receivers in this
draft.
>> I touched on this a little bit earlier,
but um, are you ever able to kind of get
a sense before the draft that that there
is going to be a lot of lot of moving
pieces, trades being made, etc. it like
does that ever kind of play out the way
you envision it doing or
>> um
you know I don't know that I would say
it that way. I think there's there's
times when
um
yeah it's a good question but I don't
really think of it in those terms. You
know I'm more focused on what we're
doing not what everyone else is doing.
Um, and I think the the higher up you
get, the more you're focused on what
you're doing, not what everyone else is
doing. And if an opportunity comes up,
then we look at it. Uh, regardless of
whether that's an opportunity to move up
or move down, and then we'll make an
assessment that that makes sense for us
or not.
>> Those conversations typically start
happening about 97.
>> Yeah, they're they're going to happen
over the next couple, you know, today
and tomorrow before the draft. You're
going to get a real sense. And we
already have, you know, a couple of
teams that that we've talked to that um
more than a couple actually that have
and and really those conversations are
just simply, hey, we'd like to move down
or we want to move up. Um and then we'll
have a discussion in the next 24 hours
about, okay, what's the cost of that or
what's you know, what are we getting for
that? and and then you have, you know,
you kind of make this call in your mind
about, yep, I do that for that and then
we wait and see what's available, you
know, when we're on the clock.
>> Yeah, that was going to be
>> it's it's it's there's a lot of moving
parts in here.
>> So, it's sometimes contingent on like,
okay, if this happens and we're engaging
re-engaging this conversation,
>> I think it's almost always contingent
upon I mean, because you're not trading
up for the spot, you're trading up for a
player. Um, and so it's always, okay, is
a player available?
>> What's your uh read on on on the top
seven picks in this first year in this
draft? Do you think there's like six
guys that will go in the top seven or do
you think this is one of those draft
classes where
>> who's the top seven?
>> Well, that's what I'm saying. I mean, do
do you feel like there's a consensus
there or do you think I mean, are your
scenarios like it could be pretty random
in that group this year based on what
teams do in front of you? Yeah, it's a
good question. Um, I certainly don't
think that all 32 teams have the same
seven guys listed from one to seven. Um,
and I don't know what the other teams
are, you know, what their lists look
like. I know what our list looks like.
Um, so I don't I don't really pay
attention to that much. Um, it's a good
question. I just I don't have enough
information to answer it really. I know
you uh you joked about never having
trading back always trading up and you
joke about
>> we I traded it back
>> in the first round. Sorry. In the first
round. In in the first round.
>> Yes. I like
>> All right. I'll go with that.
>> But just hypothetically
>> can't deny the facts.
>> Hypothetically, would it be like our
cloud of players things happen that
they're not there or the offer is just
so amazing we there's
>> Yeah, it'd be either or. Okay,
>> it'd be, you know, the scenarios would
be, okay, we're at pick eight and we've
got four guys that we love and so we
could go back to as far as 12. Um, if
there's two that we love, then we could
only go back, you know, two spots,
right?
Or someone comes in and says, "We'll
give you three first round picks to
move." You know, yeah,
may have to do that, right? So, it's
either or. Um,
but I'm not someone that just wants to
trade just to have a transaction, you
know. I
uh it's got to be really specific as to
what we're getting.
>> And some and some of that, by the way,
comes into play about who are you
trading with and what's their likelihood
that that pick is going to be late the
next year versus earlier. And so all
that comes into play. um when we're you
know making that assessment.
>> Yeah, that's what I was going to follow
up with. How much do the say trade terms
change from year to year? In other
words,
>> hypothetically, you we're going to trade
up to number three this year.
>> Do you look at past years and what that
cost or could it change every year
according to what the draft is?
>> That's a good question. I think history
is is a really valuable tool for us,
right? So, we've got the history of
trades and you know, I pour over that.
We have guys that pour over it. Um, and
then we have these point charts, right?
Which I think the good thing is is uh
almost all the teams use these point
charts now to value at least that's the
starting point. And if we're all on the
same point chart, which we all always
aren't, um,
that's the starting point. And then you
look at, hey, what historically has it
taken? And then it becomes a matter of
market, right? Some years there's a lot
of teams that want to move back and not
very many want to move up. And so, um,
that's an advantage for the team moving
up because, you know, the markets, uh,
dictates a better a better cost.
>> Mickey, you said sometimes you consider
if you're trading with another team for
a future pick, where you think they're
going to be drafting next year. If you
trade
>> your pick next year, what what what pick
will that be
>> in your mind? Yeah, that's a good
question. You're not gonna trap me on
that one.
>> Are you
>> 32? I think it's gonna be pick 32.
>> I'm gonna go with that. Trading pick 32.
>> Yeah, that's what I'm going with.
>> Does when you're talking about being
risk adverse earlier, does that like
change how you feel about potentially
trading into the top five, you know,
that that that cost to get a premium
type of pick?
>> Um,
no. I mean, if you're trading in pick
five, you know, that's you're not
looking for risk. You're looking for the
sure thing, right? So, I guess in that
sense, yeah, maybe a little bit, but you
know, I like the spot we're in. I know
we're going to get a good player. Um, so
I I can't really answer that till.
>> Was it was it Deion Jordan that year
that that trade up? Actually, that was
just Jeff. Like, was that the cheapest
it's ever been to? Was that you're an
extreme outlier or have there been
others where
>> um
Well, you know, it it's funny we've
talked about this a little bit because
when I was in Seattle, you know, Randy,
um we had pick 10 and 11 and we ended up
with pick three and six and the cost for
that those total moves were um really
good relative to today's prices. Um, and
you know, we ended up drafting Sean
Springs and Walter Jones with those two
picks and that was pretty good deal.
>> Um, really good deal.
>> Has it?
>> But the, you know, it's different now.
Um,
you know, the cost is higher generally
speaking.
>> Has that risk averse philosophy changed
over the years based on like players
that may or may not have worked out or
is it, as you were saying earlier, Yeah.
more based on like picking
>> Yeah, I higher or lower. I think we're
always affected by, you know, what we've
done in the past and I got a long past.
So, yeah, I think we're we're Yeah, it
definitely affects you. You know, we
relate to, you know, a lot of what we do
is comparison, right? This player
compared to that player, this deal
compared to, you know, a deal that we've
done in the past. And so, um, those ones
that didn't work out definitely affect,
you know, our thinking to some degree.
Can you just talking about that a little
bit when you talk about your history?
I'm sure there's been years here where
when you know you had Drew in his prime,
it's like step on the gas and go all in
now. Yeah. Versus maybe where you are
right now and kind of balancing being
aggressive versus being patient.
>> Yeah. Um is there a question there?
>> Yeah. I just What is your philosophy on
that? you know, haven't done it for a
long time. Maybe where are you right now
and and how is it hard to be patient
knowing that you may not not to say I
know you said you want to pick 32, but
knowing that where you are right now?
>> Well, I I would say it this way when you
have a Drew Brees, right? When you have
that caliber of quarterback, you're
always feeling like you're one player
away, right? And so, man, let's go get
the one player. Um, and when you have a
young quarterback and you're developing
your roster, then you're not one player
away. So, you're less inclined to give
up, you know, a number of assets uh to
get, you know, one player. Uh, that's
probably the best way I can describe it.
>> Well, where where are you guys though? I
mean, after the success you had late
last
>> Yeah, we're not one we're not one player
away. Are you are but when you were just
describing that I mean
>> are you closer to pushing the gas after
the weight last ended or or not
necessarily.
>> Yeah. I mean I wouldn't say I mean that
that's a five game stretch right or six
game stretch. So
>> I don't want to read too much into that.
We're excited. We're optimistic um about
our future but we're not
>> by no means have we arrived anywhere.
>> We have time for two or three more.
Nikki, uh I I don't know. I don't know
if you thought a lot about this at all,
but like with NIL with the COVID uh year
and the some players coming out after
six, seven years in college, 25 year old
prospects, has that like changed
>> um how you're having to evaluate some of
these guys or maybe it's a little bit
different than it was 10 years ago with
>> Yeah, I I think it's a double-edged
sword, right? Um because and we're
talking about the age of the players.
>> Yep.
On the one hand, look, there's probably
less opportunity for, you know, a big
development with the the older player.
On the other hand, we've got a lot more
information and we can do a better job
evaluating. And so, I don't necessarily
think it's a good or bad thing. Um, I I
just think it's something we're going to
have to deal with, you know, these guys.
And I look I think overall it's a good
thing that they stay in college and
develop um and they have the opportunity
to um you know one of the things about
the NIL is these guys their earning
years have expanded right because it's
not just earning it doesn't just happen
in the pros it happens in in college too
and that's a good thing for for these
guys. So um it's just something we have
to deal with and and I think we've done
a good job of that but you know the
positive thing is we get more
information.
What are the things that make you or
make an NFL team remove a player from a
board or want to avoid a player from a
risk perspective?
>> Oh man, that it can be a lot of things
really. It can be have to do with, you
know, practice habits or character. It
can happen, you know, injury uh uh
history.
I mean, there's just so many things and
maybe just the fit of the player. You
know, there may be a player that doesn't
fit in our particular scheme and as good
as we think he is, he just doesn't fit
for what we're trying to get
accomplished. So, it can be a lot of
things. Uh it's not it's never just one
thing. Last one.
>> Um, does that dynamic kickoff rules that
add like a a different element to like
especially day three for guys who maybe
are like a one skill set type player in
like like would you be able to get like
a Rashijah or whatever and in as a
priority free agent versus you know now?
>> Yeah, I I think that's more dependent
upon what your roster looks like. But
look, we have to pay, you know, we pay
attention to special teams and and uh
and the kickoff rules changes have
affected a little bit the makeup of of
your your roster in that regard. And so
there there's I wouldn't say it's a big
deal, but it is, you know, it is a u it
is variable.
>> All right. Thank you guys.